These three had elaborated Old Major's teachings into a complete system of thought,
to which they gave the name of Animalism.
Several nights a week, after Mr. Jones was asleep, they held secret meetings in
the barn and expounded the principles of Animalism to the others.
At the beginning, they met with much stupidity and apathy.
Some of the animals talked of loyalty to Mr. Jones, whom they referred to as master,
or made elementary remarks such as "Mr. Jones feeds us. If he were gone, we
should starve to death."
Others asked such questions as "Why should we care what happens after we are dead?"
or "If this rebellion is to happen anyway, what difference does it make whether we
work for it or not?"
And the pigs had great difficulty in making them see that this was contrary
to the spirit of animalism.
The stupidest questions of all were asked by Mollie, the white mare.
The very first question she asked Snowball was >> "Will there still be sugar after the
rebellion?"
>> "No. We have no means of making sugar on this farm.
Besides, you do not need sugar.
You will have all the oats and hay you want."
>> "And shall I still be allowed to wear ribbons in my mane?"
>> "Comrade, those ribbons that you are so devoted to are the badge of slavery.
Can you not understand that liberty is worth more than ribbons?"
>> Mollie agreed, but she did not sound very convinced.
The pigs had an even harder struggle to counteract the lies put about by Moses, the tame raven.
Moses, who was Mr. Jones's especial pet, was a spy and a tale-bearer.
But he was also a clever talker.
He claimed to know of the existence of a mysterious country called Sugar Candy Mountain,
to which all animals went when they died.
It was situated somewhere up in the sky, a little distance beyond the clouds, Moses said.
In Sugar Candy Mountain, it was Sunday 7 days a week.
Clover was in season all the year round, and lump sugar and linseed cake grew on the hedges.
The animals hated Moses because he told tales and did no work.
But some of them believed in Sugar Candy Mountain.
And the pigs had to argue very hard to persuade them that there was no such